<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PuTTY | rm -rf /]]></title>
  <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/categories/putty/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-22T21:00:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tim Steinbach]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PuTTY - Automatically load a profile]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/05/PuTTY-Automatically-load-a-profile/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-05T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/05/PuTTY-Automatically-load-a-profile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Create a link to PuTTY.exe and add <code>-load PROFILE</code> after the last "" in the target field.
Replace PROFILE with the name of your PuTTY profile that you created.</p>

<p><strong>Hint:</strong>
Combined with my articles on creating an SSH tunnel and the automatic connection via SSH with a public key, you can easily create a single shortcut that connects automatically and opens your tunnel so that you can surf the web more safely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH tunnel - Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/04/SSH-tunnel-Windows/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-04T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/04/SSH-tunnel-Windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After explaining the SSH tunnel for Mac, here is the Windows version.</p>

<p>(from the Mac entry)</p>

<blockquote><p>Have you ever been stuck behind a corporate firewall? (Or at school?)
It is usually fairly easy to bypass those systems using an SSH tunnel. All you need to have is a server on the Internet that allows you to log in via SSH.</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>Get a copy of PuTTY for Windows and open it.
First, enter your server data such as IP address and port.
Go to Connection – SSH – Tunnels and enter a port as “Source Port” (eg. 8888) and an asterisk (*) as destination.
Then switch to Dynamic and hit “Add”.
Then go back to your basic options and save your profile under any name.</p>

<p>As soon as you open the connection and keep it open with PuTTY you can change your browser’s proxy settings to localhost:8888 and surf the Internet through that SSH tunnel.
Since all the browsers work differently under Windows, please use Google to find out how to change the proxy settings for your particular browser.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
