<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Linux | rm -rf /]]></title>
  <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T20:53:06-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tim Steinbach]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparent background for icons]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2012/04/22/Transparent-background-for-icons/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2012/04/22/Transparent-background-for-icons</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Using xfce, most of the themes available customize the way your desktop icons look, but almost all of them add some kind of background to the icon label.
If you like the background to be transparent, you need to create one file in your home folder.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Add the following to <code>~/.gtkrc-2.0</code> (create it if it does not exist)</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2604543.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>style &quot;xfdesktop-icon-view&quot; {

XfdesktopIconView::label-alpha = 0
font_name=&quot;Sans Bold&quot;

base[NORMAL] = &quot;#ffffff&quot;
base[SELECTED] = &quot;#ffffff&quot;
base[ACTIVE] = &quot;#fefefe&quot;

fg[NORMAL] = &quot;#ffffff&quot;
fg[SELECTED] = &quot;#73B2D0&quot;
fg[ACTIVE] = &quot;#D17100&quot;
}
widget_class &quot;*XfdesktopIconView*&quot; style &quot;xfdesktop-icon-view&quot;</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>This will make the background transparent and change the font colour to white.
The configuration is straight forward, so try out what looks best for you.
Note that you might have to log out and back in for changes to take effect.</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://xubuntu.wordpress.com/2007/08/27/howto-remove-the-borders-of-your-desktop-icon-text" title="Xubuntu Blog">Xubuntu Blog</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find UUID of a hard disk]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/24/Find-UUID-of-a-hard-disk/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-24T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/10/24/Find-UUID-of-a-hard-disk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I added a new hard drive to my server. In order to make it available after each reboot (my home server shuts down over night) I needed to add it to my <code>/etc/fstab</code>.
Since it is smarter to use UUIDs instead of the <code>/dev/sdX1</code> name, I tried to find my drive’s UUID.
After a few searches in various manuals, here is how to easily find your UUID.</p>

<p>This will display all the drive’s UUIDs and also of which type they are (e.g. ext3)</p>

<p><code>blkid</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Log in to SSH automatically with a public key]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/09/17/Log-in-to-SSH-automatically-with-a-public-key/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-17T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/09/17/Log-in-to-SSH-automatically-with-a-public-key</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I find myself logging in an out of servers a dozen times a day. Entering the secure password, which is a rather long one, can become quite annoying after some time.
In order to authenticate with SSH it is also possible to use a pair of keys, a private and a public key.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First, you will need a small tool called “PuTTY Key Generator” or simply “PuTTYgen” (e.g. found here).
Hit the “Generate” button and move your mouse around until the progress bar is gone and you can see a seemingly random occurrence of symbols. This is your public key.
Now hit the button labelled “Save private key” and save it to your hard drive.
Log in to your server via SSH now and create a folder called <code>.ssh</code> (mind the dot) in your home folder, then create a file called <code>authorized_keys</code> and finally add the symbol soup that is your “Key” from the Key Generator into that file. Make sure you remove all line breaks. (I had two of them)</p>

<p>Here are the Linux commands:</p>

<pre><code>cd
mkdir .ssh
touch .ssh/authorized_keys
nano .ssh/authorized_keys
</code></pre>

<p>When you want to exit nano, hit Ctrl+X, then Enter, then Y to save the file.
After that, close your connection to the server.</p>

<p>Assuming, you already have a connection session to your server with PuTTY, all you have to do is open that session and go to the Connection->SSH->Auth settings in order to add the private key you saved a moment ago. It is the setting at the very bottom.
Also, go to Connection->Data and add your username to the input field at the top of that settings screen.
Now save the session.
When you double-click the session now, you will no longer have to enter your username or password and automatically be signed in.</p>

<p>If you find double-clicking the session too annoying, too, try this:
Create a shortcut to putty and add <code>-load XYZ</code> (replace XYZ with your session name in PuTTY) in the “target” field. The shortcut will then automatically load this session and since the session automatically logs you in, double-clicking the shortcut will be all you have to do from now on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install Oracle 10g XE under Ubuntu 10.04 x86]]></title>
    <link href="http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/09/10/Install-Oracle-10g-XE-under-Ubuntu-10.04-x86/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-10T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nequissimus.github.com/rmrf.eu/blog/2010/09/10/Install-Oracle-10g-XE-under-Ubuntu-10.04-x86</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a short tutorial on how to install the free Oracle 10g XE under Ubuntu 10.04 x86.</p>

<!--more-->


<ol>
<li>Create a swap file at least 1024 MB in size</li>
<li>Add <code>deb http://oss.oracle.com/debian unstable main non-free to /etc/apt/sources.list</code></li>
<li><p>Retrieve repository key with</p>

<p> <code>sudo wget http://oss.oracle.com/el4/RPM-GPG-KEY-oracle  -O- | sudo apt-key add -</code>
 <code>sudo apt-get update</code></p></li>
<li><p><code>sudo apt-get install oracle-xe</code> to install Oracle XE</p></li>
<li>run <code>sudo /etc/init.d/oracle-xe configure</code></li>
<li>After the installation, add the code snippet below to your ~/.bash_aliases</li>
<li>Run the sqlplus command with login sys as sysdba and the previously set password to connect to the database. Startup starts the database if it hasn’t been started automatically.</li>
</ol>


<p><em>~/.bash_aliases</em></p>

<pre><code>export ORACLE_HOME=/usr/lib/oracle/xe/app/oracle/product/10.2.0/server
export PATH=$PATH:$ORACLE_HOME/bin
export ORACLE_SID=XE
</code></pre>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://blog.btmatthews.com/?p=187">Brian’s Stuff</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
